hey everyone welcome back to this joska
playlist and today I am going to talk
about another interesting feature which
is available in the multi-user workspace
inside your Tosca Commander which is how
you can create different users and user
groups and also uh how you can manage
them okay so if you are working in a
multi-user workspace which is pretty
common when you are working within
organization or an actual project with
different team members and if you are
one of the admins within the group then
you can go ahead and create different
user groups and also different users
within that user groups okay and then
you can also assign these user groups to
different uh sections depending on which
User Group should have what kind of
access rights on your project or on your
repository okay
so where you can access the user
management uh well it is not on the top
menu bar but when you click on your root
project you will see a tab where it
displays user management
okay
so this will be only available if you
are working on a multi-user workspace
which I have already shown how to create
a multi-user workspace okay
now in order to make any changes uh in
user management you need to check out
the root folder okay so don't forget
that and once you check out that you can
then do any kind of changes in here okay
so as you can see I have already created
a few user groups which I'm going to
delete so this will show you how you can
basically delete different user groups
okay
um but do keep in mind that even if I
delete the user groups the users are
actually not deleted okay so if I have
created these three different users uh
these are not deleted okay from even if
I delete the user group
okay also in the view option I can there
is an option for show disabled users so
if I don't want these users to be
displayed here I can just check out
these enabled options for these users
and then I can just toggle around
like which users should be displayed uh
here on which should not be displayed
okay
so this is how you can toggle disabled
and enabled users uh inside your group
so by default in your multi-user
workspace there are two groups created
uh one is the admins and one is the all
users okay so whatever users you create
inside your workspace will all be listed
down here
and then some of the users will be admin
so they will be added into this group
okay by default that is admin user as
you can see you cannot disable this user
okay but you can always create more
users
so let's jump to how we can create a new
user inside a user group
but I think it will make sense if we
first create a user group right so if
you right click on your root project and
there is an option to create a user
group
so this way you can create a user group
so I can name it Tosca
specialists
okay
and then I can create another group
called Tosca design specialists
okay
so uh this way you can have different
groups based on the role assigned to
different people or you can also create
groups depending on if you have a
certain project which should have
certain access then you can create a
group for that particular project right
and then inside this we can create
different users so when you right click
on a user group you will get an option
to create a user
and here I can add any number of users
Okay so
by default they will be named user 6 but
I can always name them
okay
and
then there are different options
available
um like what kind of whether you want to
enable them if you want to disable them
later on okay
you can also provide a description like
uh
user or design specialists
User Group
okay
and then this one project
User Group
so this is just to make sure that you
can identify which User Group you are
working with
you can also specify a particular domain
if you want right
and then you can enable and disable
which I have already shown you
now there's also a setting called set
result allowed and if you uncheck this
option then this particular user will
not be able to set a result manually
okay so whatever result uh it gets from
the execution will be displayed but you
cannot set the result manually to pass
or fail okay so you can decide if you
want to allow this setting or not
and then you can also assign a
particular level so
there are like a basic uh Advanced and
also expert level Okay so
depending on the level they will have
different types of access to different
sections
um so depending on what kind of users
you are creating you can define a level
also for the group level so there is a
owning group you can decide who is the
owning group either the admins or the
all users so depending on who is the
owning group he can uh the user of that
particular group can only make the
changes okay
so these are all the different uh
options which are available with a user
group and a user which you create we
have already seen how you can delete
different users and different user
groups
and then
as I said we can create different admins
also who have got the admin permissions
okay and now let's see how we can
Define which user groups can have what
access okay so if you go to any
particular section like execution
section and go into properties
here you will see the owning group name
okay and this is by default all users
inherited for all the different sections
okay but you can always change this
for example
if I want to provide a group to a module
section
right so what I can do I can check out
this modules
and then I can change this owning group
name and there is also a viewing group
name okay so right now there is no group
assigned to this viewing group name but
once you assign this only these users
can view this particular module section
they cannot make any changes
okay and if I want to make this
something specialist right for design
specialist maybe so the design
specialist will be the owner of this
particular section module section and
the Tosca specialist can only view this
particular modules or you can also keep
it all users so all users can view this
particular section but they cannot make
any changes like uh adding modules
deleting modules or updating the modules
okay this you can do it at any level if
you want a particular component folder
where you want a particular project to
have access right so you can Define this
owning group name and viewing group name
uh using this you can then make sure
that the particular group has the right
access across your workspace okay
so this is more of increasing your
security for your user workspace if
there are multiple users working on the
same project or different projects
inside the same Repository
so there is authentication where you
will set some password for a particular
user and then there is authorization
where you will provide certain access
rights to those particular user groups
and users right so talking about uh
changing passwords or setting passwords
for different users that can also be
done right so here uh when you add a
particular user there is an option to
set password okay and as an admin I can
do this I can set a particular password
for this particular user so whenever he
tries to logs in he has to provide this
password
okay
maybe I I made some mistake in entering
the password two times so let's try
again
okay so the password is set now I can
always come back and reset this again
click on set password and then change
the password okay so this is how you can
set uh passwords for different users
within your user groups and admin can do
that
also if you want to track what the user
is doing in your workspace like what it
is opening where which text agents they
are using or where they are making
changes right so things like that if you
want to track you can also create a
personal data report
now this personal data report it will be
generated inside your workspace and uh
it will be in an Excel format so you can
always go ahead and view this
okay so right now you can see there is
no uh report here because this user
hasn't logged in yet but if I look at
admin report
okay so here you can see it is showing
me which machine ID I have used uh which
workspace ID which user ID
which user name okay uh if there are
multiple revisions uh then the creation
date
the object ID so this will tell me what
objects I'm making changes on right and
any particular comment
so this type of reports can be generated
for every user so to track their usage
okay
so this is all the functionality which
is available inside user management
inside Tosca and this you can use to
manage your users and your user groups
their access rights their
username passwords or even tracking
their usage
so that's all for this particular video
where I've shown you
um the user Management in Tosca and do
tune in to our channel to see more
interesting videos on Tosca or to learn
Tosca right from scratch